aferry.to 2019-06-20

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy and Cookie Policy Statement

AFerry Ltd is committed to protecting the privacy of its customers. This Privacy Policy applies to all the domains that are wholly managed by AFerry Ltd including www.aferry.co.uk and all AFerry trademark sites ("our sites"). 

The sites are owned by AFerry Ltd of 2morrow Court Appleford Road, Sutton Courtenay, Oxfordshire, OX14 4FH. Our company number is 04127327. We are the `data controller' of the personal information you provide to us.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy summarises what personal details we may collect from you before, during or after you use our sites and what we will do with them. You can contact us via the postal address above or [**click here to contact us**](https://www.aferry.co.uk/contact-us.htm).

Any changes to our Privacy and Cookie Policy will be posted on this page. 

### Information we collect from you

**Information you give us:** AFerry Ltd requires you to submit personal details including names, addresses, passport numbers and payment details to successfully make a travel booking. Your credit/debit card detail only stay on our system for the duration of the booking process and is encrypted using Thawte technology. Your details are maintained on our database to enable us to amend, cancel or update your relevant booking.

**Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our sites we will automatically collect information about your computer (e.g. your IP address, browser, operating system etc.) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers.

AFerry Ltd does not use your details for direct marketing purposes; however we do offer customers the opportunity to sign up to our monthly newsletters which can be found at www.aferry.co.uk. If you wish to change your mind about hearing from us, you can do so by using the unsubscribe link on our newsletters.

If you share other people's data with us, for example if you wish to make a booking for another family member, you will need to check that person consents to you providing that information to us.

### How we use the information we collect from you

We may use information about you to:

  * carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us to provide certain travel services that you request from us. This includes passing certain details about you (such as your name and the names of other travel party members), to our third party travel operators who will be providing the travel services to you;
  * ensure that content from our sites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * provide information, products and services that you request, or which we think may interest you.

By completing a booking with AFerry Ltd, you agree to receive an email shortly after the completion of your journey, asking you to review your trip. This review can be completed anonymously. By completing a review you agree that your review can be uploaded onto the relevant areas of the website for the purpose of informing other users. We reserve the right to adjust, reject, remove or use the reviews in any way that we see fit at our sole discretion. The review request should be regarded as a survey only and does not include any further commercial offers, invitations or incentives.

Where you have given your permission for us to use your personal information for particular purposes, or where we send you communications relating to our products and services, you can at any time change your preferences as to how your data is used by us by unsubscribing from our newsletters.

We may also use information about your visits to our sites to enhance your visit to our sites and to create a general demographic profile of visitors.

Telephone calls and e-mail correspondence with AFerry Ltd at the email addresses accessible through, or obtained from, this site may be recorded or monitored. By using these communication methods you are consenting to the recording and/or monitoring of your calls and emails.

### How do we store and protect your data?

We will endeavour to ensure that the personal information you submit to us is kept private and secure, and held in accordance with relevant laws. We will not sell, rent or otherwise disclose the personal information you provide to us through the sites to third parties (other than as listed below) unless we are required to do so by law.

### Where we store your data

AFerry Ltd incorporates Thawte encryption technology on all its websites to ensure your information is kept private. A Thawte SSL Certificate provides validation that our domain is registered and that we hold a valid certificate and also encrypts your information within a secure environment which is impossible to crack meaning you can book in real-time simply and securely.

### Disclosing your information

We share your personal information with certain third parties who provide services on our behalf. They only have access to the personal information they need to perform those services. They are required to keep your personal information secure and confidential and may only use it as permitted by us in accordance with this Privacy and Cookie Policy.

We may disclose your information in the following cases:

  * if we want to sell our business, or our company, we can disclose it to the potential buyer;
  * to other businesses in our group in order to assist in the provision of our services to you;
  * if we have a legal obligation to do so, or in order to protect other people's property, safety or rights;
  * we can exchange information with others to protect against fraud or credit risks;
  * to any financial institution with whom we hold an account for the purpose of verifying credit status and / or validating financial transactions.
  * When you make a booking we may need to share your personal information with the Ferry Operators, of the services you're purchasing. This information may also be shared with other third parties, including port authorities, customs, and passport offices, where this is necessary to fulfil the ferry service contract.

### How Long Do We Store Your Data?

We will not keep your data for longer than is necessary for the relevant purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Where you have made a booking, we will hold your relevant personal details to enable us to provide after-sale services and to administer the relevant warranty. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold your data is 6 years. For more information on our data retention policy, please [**contact us**](https://www.aferry.co.uk/contact-us.htm).

### Your rights

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and The Data Protection Act 2018 (DPA) you have a number of rights with regard to your personal data. 

You have the right to request from us access to and rectification or erasure of your personal data, the right to restrict processing, object to processing as well as in certain circumstances the right to data portability. 

If you have provided consent for the processing of your data, you have the right (in certain circumstances) to withdraw that consent at any time which will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent was withdrawn. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint to the Information Commissioners' Office if you believe that we have not complied with the requirements of the GDPR or DPA with regard to your personal data. Please contact us at 2Morrow Court, Sutton Courtenay, OX14 4FH, Oxfordshire, England in writing if you have any queries in relation to your rights.

### No data collected from children

Our Site is not directed at children and should not be accessed by them. We will not knowingly collect information from minors without their parent's or guardian's consent. 

### Links to other sites

Please note that our terms and conditions and our policies will not apply to other websites that you get to via a link from our sites. This includes the terms and conditions of the ferry or train operator you have booked through us who will be providing travel services to you. If you visit any of these sites please note that they have their own privacy policies and you should check these before submitting any personal data. We cannot accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

### Further information

If we change this Privacy and Cookie Policy, we will post the changes on this page. If we decide to, we may also email you.

If you have any questions regarding this policy or would like more information about the cookies used on our websites, please [**contact us**.](https://www.aferry.co.uk/contact-us.htm)

### Cookie policy

When you visit AFerry, you will automatically receive one or more cookies. The primary purpose of the cookies we use is to optimise your user experience when visiting our website. In addition, we also use third party cookies for statistics and to analyse user behaviour. This policy explains the types of cookies we use, why we use them and how you can block or remove them.

### What are cookies?

A cookie is a small file downloaded to a device when the user accesses certain websites. These cookies are then sent back to the website on each subsequent visit. This is useful because it allows a website to recognise the user's browser or device. You can find out more about cookies at [www.aboutcookies.org.](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)

### Consent

There is a notice on our home page which provides a link to our website cookie policy. If you use this website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this Privacy and Cookie Policy.

### Blocking and removing cookies

Your web browser may give you the ability to block or delete cookies if you wish to do so. Please use the "Help" menu in your browser for further information. Please note that blocking all cookies will prevent you from having the optimal experience on many websites, including our own. Therefore, we recommend that you allow the use of cookies when using our websites.

For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to the Information Commissioner's webpage on cookies: [ https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/.](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/)

### How we use cookies

Cookies on our websites may be set by us, by third parties under contract with us, or by independent third parties such as Twitter, Facebook and YouTube.

Our website uses both _session_ and _persistant_ cookies. _Session_ cookies remember information as you navigate through the site and allows the sorting and filtering of our price comparison search results. 

These cookies are removed when you end your session. _Peristant_ cookies enable our website to recognise you when you make return visits, and remain stored on your device until they are either deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

Below, we have set out the various types of cookies we use, why we use them, and includes information you can use to control or find out more about the cookies used on our website.

#### Cookie Type

#### Why we use it and additional information

#### Why we use it and additional information

Essential cookies, as their name suggests, are vital to the proper functioning of the website. They enable us to remember your selections between pages, such as routes, dates and the number of travellers, without you ever having to re-enter it.

#### Cookie Type

Performance/User Experience

#### Why we use it and additional information

We use cookies to make sure our website performs as it needs to, and to make sure the correct search results are being delivered in accordance with your selections. We also use cookies to heighten your experience by recognising whether you are a first time visitor and remembering your preferences (such as language or currency type) and previous searches.

#### Why we use it and additional information

Optimisation cookies allow us to see and track anonymous use data such as click trends, so we can be certain the site offers you a consistently smooth, functional and pleasant experience.

We use third party service providers to assist us with optimisation, such as Google Analytics. For information on these cookies, please follow [this link](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

#### Why we use it and additional information

Advertising cookies can be used by us to interact with you once you have left our website, to help you find the ferry or train that's right for you. We collect data related to your browser activity including the number of pages viewed, routes selected and searches made.

We work with Criteo, a third party service to tailor advertisements for you once you have left our website. For more information, please read their [privacy policy](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/).

#### Why we use it and additional information

We also use cookies to monitor and understand more about how our websites and services are used and accessed, which in turn lets us optimise the user experience and build a website that suits the needs of our users and drive the direction of our business. We use Google Analytics who store cookies on your device to generate anonymous reports and statistics.

Google stores this information in accordance with their [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

### Further information

If we change this Privacy and Cookie Policy, we will post the changes on this page. If we decide to, we may also email you.

If you have any questions regarding this policy or would like more information about the cookies used on our websites, please [**contact us**](https://www.aferry.co.uk/contact-us.htm)

If you wish to learn more about cookies and how to manage them, visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org/](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).
